Jeff Brozena

jeff@brozena.net | +1 (570)335-8269

SUMMARY

An operator and teacher with 5+ years in systems integration, software training/implementation, and change management at one of the country's largest privately-held Medicaid pediatric dental groups. With over 50,000 children seen per year and little chance for downtime, I stewarded the group from paper-based record-keeping to full digitization and was entrusted to set strategic direction, improve core business processes and lead complex change shortly before a cross-generational ownership transfer was expected. I leveraged software integration to catalyze systemic organizational change at scale.

My impact at this group was described positively as "like a crater" by its ownership.

EXPERIENCE

Penn State University - Research Support

Sep 2019 - present

- College of Information Sciences & Technology, Wellbeing and Health Innovation Lab
- Working to develop a conceptual and technical framework to detect mental health states using multi-modal data streams reflecting online activities.

The Smilist Management - Manager of Optimization

Feb 2018 — Aug 2018

- Process discovery, documentation, and re-engineering at a multi-site dental service organization.
- Conducted individual/group interviews and observed process to document and address systemic issues at their root cause after quickly establishing rapport with a variety of stakeholders.

Smiles 4 Keeps Pediatric Dentistry - Practice Operations

Aug 2012 - Nov 2017

- Responsible for a complete paper-to-digital transformation in the midst of a cross-generational familial ownership transfer, resulting in an accurate thirdparty valuation of business.
- Spoke publicly at American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry, Pennsylvania Academy of Pediatric Dentistry on the subjects of digitization and compliant record-keeping.

Bedrock Technology - Technician

Jan 2012 — Aug 2012

Appek Mobile Apps - Project Manager

May 2011 — Dec 2012

Penn State University - Research Assistant

May 2009 — Jan 2010

 College of Information Sciences & Technology, Human-Computer Interaction Lab

Penn State University - Software Trainer

Aug 2007 — Dec 2009

Promoted to supervisory position in June, 2009.

AWARDS

Rock Ethics Stand Up Award, Penn State University

Apr 2011

 $Emerging\ Scholars\ Fellowship, Active\ Minds, Inc.$

Jan 2011

EDUCATION

Pennsylvania State University

BS - Information Sciences & Technology

SKILLS

Leadership: Public speaking, Systems thinking, Whole systems management, Written & verbal clarity, Motivational interviewing, Situational leadership

Digital transformation: Software training, Transformational change, Change management, Strategic planning, Business analysis

Healthcare information technology (HIT): HIPAA compliance, Electronic data interchange (EDI), Electronic medical record (EMR), Analytics, SQL, Product management, Systems integration, Software integration, Electronic remittance advice (ERA), Clinical decision support

Program management: Process improvement, Project management, Process optimization, Process management, Lean Six Sigma, Kaizen

REFERENCES

Dr Ross Wezmar, DDS: Jeff worked in an organization experiencing both cross-generational and analog-to-digital transformations. He maintained the delicate balance of transitioning a 40-year-old male-dominated enterprise to a second-generation female-directed organization in the fast-evolving provider side of healthcare. Throughout the transformation he kept steady focus on the ultimate goal of a successful transition. He shepherded cross-generational familial change in a focused and intelligent manner, holding true to both the original entrepreneurial drive along with the aspirations of the second generation. The business grew and all parties came to see the need for change while retaining the drive of the original owner. Much of this success is due to Jeff continually bringing clarity and tenacity of purpose to his position as a change-maker.

Dr Katherine Wezmar Poepperling, DDS: Jeff used his tremendous intellect combined with his insight into the human spirit to propel us in such a positive direction. He has given me a gift a peace which I didn't really think was possible.